NIKHIL SINGH

4715 Altha St, Raleigh, NC 27606 • 281-455-2381 • nikhilsingh@outlook.com • www.nikhilsingh.me

PROFILE

I've provided customer service for 7+ years: first representing patients, moving on to internal customer support as an analyst for Revenue Operations, and later as an IT analyst supporting the Operations team.

I currently represent business customers as a liaison to internal Compliance and Legal teams and am looking to apply my skills in a new industry.

EXPERIENCE

DaVita Kidney Care, Malvern, PA Analyst, Setup Risk Management 1/2016 - Present

- Mitigate company risk by:
 - managing potential issues reported by internal customers
 - guarding patient privacy through responsible use of data
 - preserving confidentiality of ongoing legal investigations
 - working across teams to develop technical solutions to prevent breach of regulations
- Educate the Compliance and Legal teams on healthcare industry standards and serve as an interpreter to facilitate swifter, less complicated discourse for 10-15 requests each week
- Conduct data research and communicate findings for Medicaid audits, each involving 7,000-12,000 claims, to ensure leadership can speak intelligently and accurately about any financial discrepancies
- Streamline and document workflow processes and create custom SQL tables, queries, forms, and reports for the team

DaVita Kidney Care, Malvern, PA Applications Support Analyst, Information Technology 2/2012 - 12/2015

- Collaborated with Revenue Operations customers as a representative of IT, built on their research through SQL queries, and implemented creative solutions within the limitations of the electronic billing systems
- Taught myself to read and reproduce code for electronic claim files to verify accurate billing to high volume payers through an external clearinghouse

EDUCATION

BA, EconomicsThe University of Texas at Austin
December 2008

SKILLS

- SQL
- Microsoft Office
- Microsoft Access
- Microsoft SharePoint
- Adobe Photoshop
- Adobe InDesign
- HTML
- CSS

RECOGNITION

2017: Awards for exemplifying values of team and service excellence

2015: Award for IT guiding principle of teamwork

2012: Award for service excellence

2010: Recognized as teammate of the month for emphasis on process improvement

DaVita Kidney Care, Malvern, PA Payer Specialist, Revenue Operations 5/2011 - 12/2011

- Independently executed trend analyses and reporting on a monthly basis to improve efficiency within the billing infrastructure for 6 states and over 50 insurance payers
- Reduced monthly average outstanding customer support tickets from 100 to 30 over a period of 3 months by developing a more effective prioritization system

DaVita Kidney Care, Malvern, PA

6/2010 - 4/2011

Patient Account Representative, Revenue Operations

- Analyzed payment metrics to ensure that patients' insurance policies were reimbursing correctly, and if not, communicated with payer representatives to determine root causes

DaVita Kidney Care, Malvern, PA

2/2010 - 5/2010

Accounts Receivable Assistant, Revenue Operations

- Supported account representatives by completing billing adjustment projects and investigating issues with insurance payers
- Promoted within first 3 months

National Instruments, Austin, TX

1/2008 - 5/2008

Intern, Investor Relations

- Analyzed competitors to determine how to better attract investors and sell-side analysts

ABOUT ME

I can speak, read, and write Hindi

Likes:

- reading
- drawing
- wildlife trivia
- comic books
- peanut butter

Dislikes:

- weak WiFi signal
- sour things